hello and welcome to the 15th tutorial
on how to program and gript 2 so let's
open our NPC and scroll down to the
bottom of the for Loop now let's make
the NPC run a bit faster and smoother
let's change this to
0.5 the loop will Loop faster because
the the delay in it is lower which will
make the NPC run faster and smoother so
anyway let's take this out in the
beginning to change the Oni
and add it into
the for Loop it doesn't matter if we add
it into it or outside of it since we're
only beginning calling it once but I'm
just going to add it
inside also inside the for Loop I'm
going to add this doer is equal to three
this will change the direction to right
the same with this we can also add it
outside the for before it but we're just
going to add it
inside so Watch What Happens now
the NPC runs to the right it's very
smooth and then it just stops and still
running in place let's open the NPC and
after the for
Loop let's add some code to make it stop
running let's make it let's change the
Oni to
idle then go here
sleep 1 second glay a
second then change the direction to two
so when we save this and
upload moves to the
right looks down Waits a second then
looks down then it just
stops let's say we want to move
backwards well we just copy the for Loop
and we take out the first parameter that
changes the N value here's the thing in
the first for Loop the we created an N
value called an N variable called I mean
called n i mean a temp variable called
an made it four then once it was 20 it
broke the L broke the loop currently
it's 20 now here we can just take this
out n is is 20 right now
it doesn't just and the the variable
doesn't just stop once the for Loop is
over temp variables only get deleted
when the function is over so it's
currently still 20 here we can just get
rid of the first parameter or add null
I'll just put nothing there then change
this line to is greater than four this
is going to make it so as long as the x
value is greater than four it's going to
walk it's going to do whatever is here
then let's change this last parameter to
minus 0.2 so it's going to go back it's
going to go to the
left it's going to subtract the x-axis
make it go left until it reaches four
then it's going to break the loop and we
can change direction to one to make it
face
left then just copy this code
here and put it under the for
Loop oh and add a sleep here so there's
a delay between the running and the
waiting same here even though it doesn't
matter right now but we'll get we'll see
what we'll add later so let's save
it upload it's going to run to the
right and stop wait a second look down
wait a second then go back to the
left it's going to look to the left wait
a second look down then wait a second
and do nothing now let's say we want it
to look go back and forth over and over
and over and
over
infinitely what we would do is make it
as I like to call a function
Loop what this is is you
put on player enters the name of the
current function which is on player
enters and semicolon this pretty much
calls a function it's going to jump it's
going to read this line and jump
straight to whatever function is being
called which is currently the function
it's in so it's going to read this and
jump way back up to here and go back
down this code do it over and over and
over again and over and over and over
again it's just going to keep going back
down back to here then going back up and
then back down and then back up it's
going to keep going left and right o
forever really There's No Limit how many
times you can Loop a function in fact if
we wanted to we could change this to on
created instead it would jump to
oncreated and run this function again
but then nothing would happen so we want
to just do
on player enters it's going to jump back
to this function run it
again so let's
upload as you can see the NPC is running
to the
right running waiting running to the
left waiting then running back to the
right and it'll do that forever
now so anyway that's it for this
tutorial I taught you a bit about how to
Loop a function and how to call other
functions too and jump to other
functions and that concludes this
tutorial and I'll see you later bye